Here I have the example,
"If I'm skilled at poker,
then I'm gonna win a bunch of money."
So go to the casino,
I won a bunch of money playing poker
and I am tempted to conclude
that therefore, I am skilled at poker.
Okay, so lots of people might actually believe this,
this would be a very reasonable
fallacy that a lot of people would make.
Let's try to analyze it and I claim this is not true.
And the Liz idea is that just 'cause I won
a bunch of money, I might've just gotten lucky,
I might be terrible at poker, but I got really lucky.
So I cannot claim
that I am skilled at poker from this argument.
So let's try to analyze the structure of this argument.
First I have, if I'm skilled at poker,
I'm gonna give that a P,
then I will win money, I'm gonna give that as a Q.
So that was my first premise, if P, then Q.
So I'll write this as P implies Q, that is my first premise.
Next up I say, I won money playing poker.
So this is asserting Q.
And then what we're saying is P implies Q
and I'm gonna copy it over here
so that we have it all in place.
P implies Q.
Then you assume the conclusion
and you're going to get, I'm skilled at poker.
So the logical form that you have here is P implies Q,
then Q, and then you get out P.
But that wasn't modus pos, that wasn't modus tones,
it was none of these.
And the problem here
is that you're kind of arguing by the converse.
It's Q implies P would be the converse of the statement,
not P implies Q.
If you had Q implies P here,
then you could icdate Q and get P,
but not the other way around.
So this is trying to use
the converse of the statement and we know that a converse
is not logically equivalent to the original statement.
So this argument does not work.
So this argument does not work
and we are going to say that it is invalid,
I disagree with this logical structure.